Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Hi everyone.
大家好。
My name is Kathryn and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Kathryn，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are dealing with a house that is filled with different types of bugs.
今天我们要讲一个房子里到处都是各种虫子的事。
Ew, bugs.
呃，虫子。
Well, it's summertime so it's not that uncommon but not a pleasant thing to deal with.
嗯，现在是夏天，所以这并不罕见，但处理起来可不是什么愉快的事。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to call an exterminator.
所以我们打算叫一个灭虫员。
So you might be asking yourself what that is but before we explain, why don't you listen
你可能在想那是什么，但在我们解释之前，不如先听一遍
to the dialogue for the first time.
对话。
Hi, did you call for an exterminator?
你好，是你叫的灭虫员吗？
Yes, thank goodness you're here.
是的，谢天谢地你来了。
These bugs are driving us crazy.
这些虫子快把我们逼疯了。
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
我们遇到的是什么害虫？
We just bought this house and it is infected with just about everything.
我们刚买了这栋房子，它几乎被所有东西侵占了。
We have termites in the wood, cockroaches all over the place and last night I saw a
木头里有白蚁，到处都是蟑螂，昨晚我还看到一只
huge rat out in the backyard.
巨大的老鼠在后院。
Well there's nothing that we can handle.
嗯，没有我们处理不了的。
I'll spray the floorboards and walls to get rid of the cockroaches but the termites will
我会喷洒地板和墙壁来消灭蟑螂，但白蚁会更难处理。
be harder to get rid of.
更难清除。
We will have to cover the entire house and fumigate it.
我们必须覆盖整栋房子并进行熏蒸。
Unfortunately, that means you will have to find a place to stay for the next three days.
不幸的是，这意味着你接下来三天得找个地方住。
No problem.
没问题。
Let's get rid of the bugs.
咱们把这些虫子消灭掉吧。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have six key words that we've chosen out for you.
现在我们为你挑选了六个关键词。
Let's take a look at those now on Language Takeaway.
让我们在“语言要点”环节看看这些词。
Well Marco you've already told our users the very first word that would be exterminator.
嗯，Marco，你已经告诉我们的用户第一个词是“exterminator”（灭虫员）。
What is an exterminator?
什么是灭虫员？
It's a person, right?
是指一个人，对吧？
That's right, it's a person that has the job to exterminate or to delete or eliminate different
没错，是指以消灭或清除各种虫子或害虫为职业的人。
types of bugs or pests.
各种类型的虫子或害虫。
So an exterminator's job is to kill bugs.
所以灭虫员的工作就是杀死虫子。
That's right.
没错。
And usually an exterminator comes to your home or your office to do this, right?
通常灭虫员会到你家或办公室来做这件事，对吧？
That's right.
是的。
So maybe in your house you have a lot of different types of bugs.
所以也许你家里有各种不同类型的虫子。
Maybe you have, I don't know, spiders.
比如，我不知道，蜘蛛。
So an exterminator will come and he will try to get rid of the spiders.
所以灭虫员会来，他会试着清除这些蜘蛛。
Great.
太好了。
So an exterminator in a general sense gets rid of pests.
所以灭虫员通常是指清除害虫的人。
And pest is our next word.
而害虫是我们的下一个词。
That's right, a pest.
没错，害虫。
Now we're talking about bugs and they can be considered a sort of pest.
现在我们说的是虫子，它们可以被视为一种害虫。
Well pest though is a more general term, right?
不过害虫是一个更广义的词，对吧？
So you can say pest about something like rats or mice.
所以你可以用害虫来形容像老鼠或耗子之类的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So basically some type of animal that is very annoying and also causes some sort of harm
所以基本上是指某种非常烦人并且会造成某种伤害的动物，
or danger.
或者危险。
Right.
对。
So there was a movie if I remember correctly in the 1990s.
我记得有一部电影，是1990年代的。
It was terrible and it was called The Pest.
那部电影很糟糕，名字叫《害虫》。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And it's all about this person who is very annoying.
电影讲的是一个非常烦人的人。
So you can even say an annoying person or a bothersome person is a pest.
所以你甚至可以说一个烦人的人或讨厌的人就是害虫。
That's right.
没错。
You're such a pest.
你真是个讨厌鬼。
Okay, so obviously our home is filled with bugs and that's what the person said that
好吧，显然我们的家里到处都是虫子，这就是那个人说的。
it is infested.
这里到处都是害虫。
Okay, so a place like an office building or like you said Marco, a home is infested if
好的，所以像办公楼这样的地方，或者像你Marco说的，一个家如果被某种东西充斥，就可以说“infested”。
it is filled with something.
就是被某种东西填满了。
And so infested means it's filled with something bad.
所以“infested”意味着被不好的东西填满了。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case the house is infested with bugs.
所以在这个例子里，房子被虫子侵扰了。
They're living upstairs, downstairs, in the basement, in the kitchen, they're everywhere.
它们住在楼上、楼下、地下室、厨房，到处都是。
That's right.
没错。
And she said that we, well actually they have termites in the wood.
她说我们，实际上他们家的木头里有白蚁。
All right, so termites are a special kind of bug that almost always live in wood, right?
好吧，所以白蚁是一种特殊的虫子，几乎总是生活在木头里，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're little bugs that I think eat the wood.
它们是一种小虫子，我觉得它们吃木头。
And this is why they're so dangerous because they make the house weak because they eat
这就是为什么它们这么危险，因为它们会吃掉支撑房子的所有木头，让房子变得脆弱。
off all the wood that supports it.
吃掉所有支撑房子的木头。
So we can say the house fell down because it was infested with termites.
所以我们可以说，房子倒塌了，因为它被白蚁侵扰了。
That's right, termites.
没错，白蚁。
And also we have a very common pest or a bug.
还有一种非常常见的害虫或虫子。
We have cockroaches.
我们有蟑螂。
Oh, I hate these and they're everywhere this summer.
哦，我讨厌它们，今年夏天到处都是。
Cockroaches come in different sizes.
蟑螂有不同的体型大小。
Some are big, some are small, but they're very, very strong bugs.
有些大，有些小，但它们是非常非常顽强的虫子。
They can live through anything.
它们能扛过任何东西。
That's right.
没错。
They're small, usually brown, but sometimes I think you can see black cockroaches.
它们很小，通常是棕色的，但有时我觉得也能看到黑色的蟑螂。
That's right.
没错。
And they love to be near food and decaying things like garbage bins.
而且它们喜欢靠近食物和腐烂的东西，比如垃圾桶。
That's right.
没错。
So a very common type of pest, cockroach.
所以一种很常见的害虫就是蟑螂。
And in order to get rid of termites and cockroaches and all these types of bugs, we have to fumigate
为了消灭白蚁、蟑螂和所有这些虫子，我们得熏蒸
the house.
房子。
Okay, so this is one method that the exterminator uses to kill bugs.
好的，这是灭虫员用来杀死虫子的一种方法。
And like in the dialogue, when you fumigate a house, basically you fill the house with
就像对话里说的，当你熏蒸房子时，基本上就是用
fumes or gases that kill bugs.
烟雾或气体来杀死虫子。
So people like you and me, we can't be in the house when that happens, right?
所以像你我这样的人，在熏蒸时不能待在房子里，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Actually, if you see an exterminator, he will always fumigate wearing a mask so he doesn't
实际上，如果你看到灭虫员，他总会戴着口罩进行熏蒸，这样他就不会
inhale those poisonous gas.
吸入那些有毒气体。
Right.
对。
So it's very dangerous for people and you'll have to make sure you talk to your exterminator
所以这对人来说非常危险，你必须确保和灭虫员沟通好，
to make sure that the gases he's using aren't getting into your body.
确保他用的气体不会进入你的身体。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
好的，那我们再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Hi, did you call for an exterminator?
嗨，是你叫的灭虫员吗？
Yes, thank goodness you're here.
是的，谢天谢地你来了。
These bugs are driving us crazy.
这些虫子快把我们逼疯了。
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
我们面对的是哪种害虫？
We just bought this house and it is infected with just about everything.
我们刚买了这栋房子，它几乎被所有东西侵占了。
We have termites in the wood, cockroaches all over the place, and last night I saw a
木头里有白蚁，到处都是蟑螂，昨晚我还看到
huge rat out in the backyard.
后院有只大老鼠。
Well there's nothing that we can handle.
嗯，没什么是我们搞不定的。
I'll spray the floorboards and walls to get rid of the cockroaches, but the termites will
我会喷洒地板和墙壁来消灭蟑螂，但白蚁
be harder to get rid of.
更难处理。
We will have to cover the entire house and fumigate it.
我们得覆盖整栋房子并进行熏蒸。
Unfortunately, that means you will have to find a place to stay for the next three days.
不幸的是，这意味着你们得找个地方住三天。
No problem.
没问题。
Let's get rid of the bugs.
咱们把虫子消灭掉吧。
All right, so now we've chosen three key phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
好的，现在我们在流利度构建器中为你挑选了三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Well, this first phrase comes from the very beginning of today's dialogue.
嗯，第一个短语来自今天对话的开头。
The second person in the dialogue says, these bugs are driving us crazy.
对话中的第二个人说：“这些虫子快把我们逼疯了。”
So, to drive someone crazy.
所以，“把某人逼疯”。
Okay, so if you're driving someone crazy, it means that you're making them crazy.
好的，如果你把某人逼疯，意思是你让他们发疯。
All right, so it could be you're making them angry or you're making them frustrated, but
对，可能是你让他们生气，或者你让他们沮丧，但
it has nothing to do with cars, right?
这和车没关系，对吧？
Yeah, yeah, there's no driving involved.
是啊，是啊，不涉及开车。
So driving here means making.
所以这里的“逼”意思是“让”。
You're making me crazy.
你让我发疯。
You're really making me frustrated.
你真的让我很沮丧。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case, the animals, the bugs were driving them crazy.
所以在这个例子里，动物、虫子把他们逼疯了。
They were so annoying that they were just, they were very irritated.
它们太烦人了，以至于他们非常恼火。
So I could do something, Marco, that will drive you crazy.
所以我可以做点事，Marco，会把你逼疯。
I could tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap.
我可以敲、敲、敲、敲、敲、敲、敲。
That's right.
没错。
That's driving me crazy.
那快把我逼疯了。
Doesn't it annoy you?
这不会让你烦吗？
Yes.
会。
So I'll stop.
那我停下来。
So it doesn't drive you crazy anymore.
这样就不会再把你逼疯了。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so now obviously bugs are driving them crazy and she went on to explain that it's
好的，显然虫子把他们逼疯了，然后她接着解释说
because the house is infested with just about everything.
因为房子几乎被所有东西侵占了。
Well, this is a great phrase because we can say it in a lot of different contexts.
嗯，这是个很棒的短语，我们可以在很多不同的语境中使用。
In this context, it means there is not everything, every single bug in the house, but just about
在这个语境里，意思不是房子里有所有东西、每一种虫子，而是“几乎
everything.
所有东西”。
That means almost every bug you can think of is in this house.
这意味着你能想到的几乎所有虫子都在这个房子里。
That's right.
没错。
So it's kind of a way of exaggerating also because obviously, well, they have cockroaches,
所以这也是一种夸张的说法，因为显然，嗯，他们有蟑螂，
they have termites, but they're saying we have a lot of different types of bugs.
有白蚁，但他们在说我们有很多不同类型的虫子。
We have just about everything that you can imagine.
我们几乎有你想象得到的所有东西。
You could even say, this restaurant has just about every Chinese dish you could ever think
你甚至可以说，这家餐厅几乎有你想到的所有中国菜。
of.
That's not true.
那不是真的。
It doesn't have every single one, but it has a lot.
它没有每一道菜，但有很多。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so that's the way that you use just about everything.
好的，这就是“几乎所有东西”的用法。
And for our final phrase, we use it a little bit earlier on.
至于最后一个短语，我们之前用了一点。
Let's explain it a little bit.
我们来稍微解释一下。
When we're talking about bugs, we want to get rid of bugs.
当我们谈论虫子时，我们想摆脱虫子。
This is why we call the exterminator, to get rid of the cockroaches.
这就是我们叫灭虫员的原因，为了消灭蟑螂。
You might hear this phrase a lot when you're watching movies about gangsters or mobsters
你在看关于黑帮或匪徒的电影时，可能会经常听到这个短语
like The Sopranos, the TV show, get rid of him.
比如电视剧《黑道家族》里的“干掉他”。
So this is a phrase that means, in this case, to kill something or to kill someone, to get
所以这个短语在这里的意思是，杀死某物或某人，摆脱它
rid of it, to get rid of him.
摆脱他。
To not have it anymore.
不再拥有它。
So rid means to get away or to throw away.
所以 rid 的意思是远离或扔掉。
But in this case, you're not just throwing it away, you're killing these bugs.
但在这里，你不只是扔掉，而是在杀死这些虫子。
That's right.
没错。
So we want to get rid of the bugs.
所以我们想摆脱这些虫子。
Now obviously, as you said, we can also throw away, for example, these shoes are too old.
显然，就像你说的，我们也可以扔掉，比如这双鞋太旧了。
I'm going to get rid of them.
我要把它们扔掉。
Or, hey Marco, this milk smells funny.
或者，嘿 Marco，这牛奶闻起来怪怪的。
Can you get rid of it?
你能把它处理掉吗？
Very good.
很好。
So that's the way that you would use that phrase, to get rid of something.
这就是你使用这个短语的方式，to get rid of something。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the very last time and we're back to talk
所以我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来继续聊
a little bit more.
一会儿。
Hi, did you call for an exterminator?
你好，是你叫的灭虫员吗？
Yes, thank goodness you're here.
是的，谢天谢地你来了。
These bugs are driving us crazy.
这些虫子快把我们逼疯了。
What sort of pests are we dealing with?
我们面对的是哪种害虫？
We just bought this house and it is infected with just about everything.
我们刚买了这栋房子，它几乎被所有东西感染了。
We have termites in the wood, cockroaches all over the place.
木头里有白蚁，到处都是蟑螂。
And last night I saw a huge rat out in the backyard.
昨晚我还在后院看到一只大老鼠。
Well there's nothing that we can't handle.
嗯，没有我们处理不了的事。
I'll spray the floorboards and walls to get rid of the cockroaches, but the termites will
我会喷洒地板和墙壁来消灭蟑螂，但白蚁会
be harder to get rid of.
更难清除。
We will have to cover the entire house and fumigate it.
我们必须覆盖整栋房子并进行熏蒸。
Unfortunately, that means you will have to find a place to stay for the next three days.
不幸的是，这意味着你需要在接下来的三天里找个地方住。
No problem.
没问题。
Just get rid of the bugs.
只要把虫子消灭掉就行。
So bugs.
说到虫子。
Everyone loves bugs, right?
每个人都喜欢虫子，对吧？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I am actually okay with termites or for example cockroaches.
我其实对白蚁或蟑螂之类的还行。
They're a little bit weird, but I actually really dislike spiders.
它们有点奇怪，但我真的很讨厌蜘蛛。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
So you're okay with cockroaches, but spiders make you nervous.
所以你对蟑螂还行，但蜘蛛让你紧张。
Yeah.
是的。
Spiders are...
蜘蛛是……
Well, the thing is, spiders can actually hurt you.
嗯，问题是蜘蛛真的会伤害你。
That's right.
没错。
And cockroaches generally cannot.
而蟑螂通常不会。
They're gross.
它们很恶心。
They're dirty.
它们很脏。
But spiders, there are very, very many kinds of dangerous spiders out there that are poisonous.
但蜘蛛，外面有很多很多种危险的蜘蛛是有毒的。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, termites, nothing's going to happen.
所以比如白蚁，什么都不会发生。
Or cockroaches, they're nasty.
或者蟑螂，它们很讨厌。
Not unless your house is weakened by hundreds of millions of termites.
除非你的房子被数亿只白蚁削弱了。
That's right.
没错。
But for example, I think other people have snakes sometimes as pests because they live
但比如，我想其他人有时会有蛇作为害虫，因为他们住在
in areas that have a lot of snakes or mice because snakes are attracted by mice.
有很多蛇或老鼠的地区，因为蛇被老鼠吸引。
That's right.
没错。
So some people keep cats for that reason.
所以有些人为此养猫。
They want the cats, especially on farms, the cats to catch the mice or to scare the snakes
他们想要猫，尤其是在农场，让猫抓老鼠或吓跑蛇
away.
走。
But I don't really have a problem with snakes or spiders, but I do have a problem with scorpions.
但我对蛇或蜘蛛没什么问题，但我对蝎子有问题。
Oh, scorpions.
哦，蝎子。
If you live close to a desert or a very dry area, scorpions, they really scare me.
如果你住在沙漠或非常干燥的地区附近，蝎子真的让我害怕。
I've seen on, I think, Discovery Channel that in Australia, they're very common.
我在探索频道上看到过，在澳大利亚，它们很常见。
And so not only scorpions, but also spiders.
所以不仅是蝎子，还有蜘蛛。
So whenever you put your shoes on, you have to check that there's nothing in it.
所以每次你穿鞋时，都得检查里面有没有东西。
That's right.
没错。
Also, shower drains.
还有，淋浴排水口。
You know where the water goes down the hole in the shower?
你知道淋浴时水从那个洞里流下去的地方吗？
Oftentimes you get things like scorpions in the desert areas that come out of the drain.
在沙漠地区，经常会有蝎子之类的东西从排水口出来。
Really?
真的吗？
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
That looks like something from a horror movie or something.
那看起来像恐怖电影里的东西。
Yeah.
是的。
All of a sudden, you're in the shower and there's pests coming out of the drain.
突然之间，你在淋浴，害虫从排水口爬出来。
That's nasty.
真恶心。
Terrifying.
太可怕了。
All right.
好吧。
So a lot of different types of kind of scary bugs and pests.
所以有很多不同类型的可怕虫子和害虫。
But we would like to know if you've ever had an infestation in your home or what pests
但我们想知道，你的家里是否曾经有过虫害，或者你害怕什么害虫
are you afraid of?
？
So let us know, our website is EnglishPod.com.
所以请告诉我们，我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys next time.
我们下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye bye.
拜拜。